(GRUNTS )
(YELPS )
All right, get out of the way.
Get out of the way!
大丈夫、よけて
よけて！
Come here! Come here!
こっちへ！こっちへ！
(PEOPLE GRUNTlNG)
Move, move!
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
どいて、どいて！
こっちへ、こっちへ
This is Scott. Slow down the evac!
We are coming in too hot!
こちらスコット、もっとゆっくり！
混乱してる！
Colonel, come in!
大佐、応答を！
MAN 1 : Move it back!
MAN 2 : Oh, my God, where are we?
男  1 : もどって!
男  2 : オーマイガッ！どこ？
WOMAN 1 : What is this place?
女1 : ここはどこ？
SCOTT: Move away from the gate!
スコット：ゲートから離れて！
(GROANlNG)
-Where are we?
-MAN 3: Where is this?
-どこ
-男3: ここはどこなんだ？
Why didn't we come through to Earth?
地球につながってたのでは？？
There's no time to explain. Off to the side!
説明している時間はない。端に寄って！
WOMAN 2: What's going on?
女性2:どういうこと？
SCOTT: All right.
Come on, come on, come on.
スコット:大丈夫
こっちへ、こっちへ。
(PEOPLE SHOUTlNG)
This is Scott. Come in!
こちらスコット。応答を！
Colonel, come in!
大佐、応答を！
-l need a medic!
-Over here!
-医療班！
-こっちよ！
JOHANSEN: Can you move your fingers?
VOLKER: No. l think my arm's broken.
ヨハンセン:指を動かせる？
ヴォルカー:いや、折れてると思う。
Okay, just hold your arm there
and we'll put it in a sling, okay?
固定するわ、OK？
(SHOUTlNG CONTlNUES )
(YELLS )
(PANTlNG)
(ECHOlNG) Keep calm. Keep coming.
(反響) 落ち着いて、続いて。
(GRUNTlNG)
Clear this area.
There could still be more incoming.
クリア。
もっとくるかもしれない。
(GRUNTS )
(ARMSTRONG COUGHlNG)
-Are you okay?
-Yeah.
-大丈夫ですか？
-あぁ。
We've got to move. Move!
-移動して、移動！
Where the hell are we?
どこなんだ？
-Greer? Where's Colonel Young?
-He was right behind me.
グリアー？大佐はどこだ？
-自分の真後ろにいました。
(GRUNTS )
(PEOPLE SCREAMlNG)
-Move. Move. Move.
-SCOTT: Ouiet!
-移動して、移動。
-スコット：静かに！
-GREER: Stay calm !
-Move. Excuse me.
グリアー：冷静に！
-ちょっと、失礼！！
GREER: Keep it down!
グリアー：静かに！
Move. Move. Move. Move. Move.
ちょっと、移動するわ。
Colonel? Colonel?
大佐？大佐？
Don't move.
動かすな。
(PANTlNG) Where are... Where are we?
われわれ…、われわれはどこに？
l don't know, sir. Are you...
大佐、わかりません。
You're in charge, okay?
指揮権を移譲する。いいか？
You're...
あなたは…
Sir?
大佐？
(GASPS )
-T.J.!
-JOHANSEN: l'm coming!
T.J.！
ヨハンセン：いきます！
GREER: Move back, people!
Coming through!
グリアー：下がって！
通るよ！
JOHANSEN: Let's go! Move, move, move!
GREER: Get back, people.
ヨハンセン：いこう！
グリアー：みな、下がれ！
-ls he okay?
-l don't know.
彼は大丈夫か？
わからないわ。
WRAY: Get back!
レイ：下がれ！
Wallace! What is this place?
ウォレス！ここはどこだ？
-Look, l just did what Rush told me...
-Where is he?
ちょうどラッシュに同じことを聞こうと…
彼はどこだ？
l don't know. He went through ahead of me.
わからない。僕の前にゲートを抜けたけど。
Rush! Rush! Eli, help me find him.
ラッシュ！ラッシュ！イーライ、探すのを手伝ってくれ。
What, l...
あぁ。
(ENGlNE WHlRRlNG)
MAN 5: What's that?
男５：あれはなんだ？
What in the hell was that?
あれはなんだ？
l don't know. Look,
わからない。みろ？
Sergeant, l need you
to get these people settled.
軍曹、みなを落ち着かせるのにきみの助けが必要だ。
And you find out who and what we've got.
Nobody leaves this room.
それから、われわれの装備と人員を確認しろ。
だれも部屋から出すな。
Yes, sir.
イエス、サー。
Eli! Now!
イーライ！
(TYPlNG)
ELl: The core of the planet
is the power source.
イーライ：星のコアは動力源だ。
You have to channel it into the weapon
to destroy the enemy ship.
敵を破壊するため、兵器にパワーを与えねばならない。
-MAN:: Can't do it, dude:
-Uh, doing it.
男：できないよ。
いや、やるんだ。
It's one of those programmer's jokes,
a probIem that can't be soIved:
問題は解決できないよ。
-Already solved it.
-No, you didn't:
既にそれは解決した。
いや、できてない。
Just shut up! Watch this.
だまれ！これをみろ。
-What the hell!
-What happened?
いったいどうなってる！
なにが起こった？
Nothing happened.
l'm back at the beginning of the level.
何も。
最初のレベルに戻った。
-You're so fuII of yourseIf:
-No. No, no, no. lt worked.
うぬぼれすぎｗ
いや、いやいや、やったよ。
-The firing code locked in.
-Whatever:
発射コードがロックされた。
なんなりと
That was extremely unsatisfying.
それは納得いかないな。
Eli Wallace?
イーライ ウォレス？
Actually, Eli's not here right now.
実は、イーライは今ここにはいない。
Okay, okay. Whatever you guys think
that l did, l swear you got the wrong guy.
OK。OK。僕がそうだと思ってるんだろ。違うと誓うよ。
Do l look like someone
who'd be standing here
ここに突っ立てる私がどう見える？
if l didn't already know
everything there is to know about you?
君についてのすべてをしらないとでも？
-Yeah, not really.
-Right.
わかった。ちがうよ。
よし。
ELl: Who are you?
イーライ：だれ？
Dr. Nicholas Rush. May we come in?
ニコラス ラッシュ博士。入っても？
Why?
どうして？
You just spent a great deal of time recently
かなりの時間かかるからさ。
playing an online fantasy game
called Prometheus:
プロメテウスというオンラインファンタジーゲームをやってるね？
(LAUGHS )
Big Brother's got nothing better to do?
なにか問題でも？
Last night you solved
the Dakara weapons puzzle.
昨夜、君はダカラ兵器のパズルを解いたね。
Yeah, a month of my life went into that.
あぁ、人生の一ヶ月をかけた
You know what happens
when you solve that thing? Nothing.
なにがおこったかしってるか？なにも。
We're here. That happened.
われわれがここにいる。おこったじゃないか。
To complete that particular puzzle,
エイリアンの言語で書かれた
you had to solve
a millennia-old mathematical proof,
一万年前の数学的証明をあの特殊なパズルを
written in another language.
完成させるために君は解いたんだ。
For that, you've won something of a prize.
そのために、君はちょっとした賞を獲得したんだ。
Well, whatever it is,
l'll take the cash equivalent.
それで、賞金か何かならうけとるけど。
There isn't one.
賞金ではない。
lt's a non-disclosure agreement.
機密保持契約書だ。
Non-disclosure?
機密保持？
So, you guys really embedded
a top-secret problem into a game,
それで、あんたたちは、本当に誰かが解くかもしれない
hoping someone like me would solve it?
最高機密の問題をゲームに埋め込んだの？
Yup.
あぁ。
So, what do you need me for now?
それで、俺が必要？
l assure you,
it'll be worth your while to sign it.
保証するよ。
サインして間違いはない。
And if l don't?
それで、サインしなかったら？
We'll beam you up to our spaceship.
宇宙船に君を転送する。
(LAUGHS )
Right. l think l want my lawyer
to look it over first.
わかった、まず俺の弁護士に
確認してもらうよ。
And by ''lawyer,''
l assume you mean ''mother.''
弁護士でなく、母親じゃないのか。
So, we'll just agree then
that l will call you.
それは、同意するときは電話あするよ。
(WHOOSHlNG)
(GASPS )
What the...
なんだ…
Welcome aboard the Hammond, Eli.
戦艦ハモンドへようこそ。
Yes, that is planet Earth,
and yes, you are on a spaceship.
あぁ、あれは地球だね。
宇宙船内にいるのか。
We need your help, Eli.
君の助けが必要だ、イーライ。
To be honest,
l don't know how long it's going to take.
正直に結うと、どのくらい時間がかかるかわからないんだ。
l should call my mom
to tell her where l am.
ママにどこにいるのか電話しなきゃ。
That's probably not going to work up here.
たぶん、ここでは使えない。
(CHUCKLES ) Right.
わかった。
You can speak to her on the way.
途中で電話できるよ。
There's a cover story you'll have to follow.
カバーストーリを用意してる。
l'm sorry. On the way to?
すまない、途中でって？
To another planet,
21 light years from here.
別の惑星へ行く。
21光年先だ。
(STAMMERlNG) l can't go.
l have things that...
いけないよ。
いろいろあるし…
We know about your mother's condition.
君のお母さんの状態は知ってる。
You just know everything, don't you?
すべてを知ってるんだよね？
We also know that
you are currently unemployed,
今無職だということも、
and that your mother's
medical coverage is
君の母親の健康上の問題が
an ongoing issue.
進行中だということも知っている。
We'll see she gets the best available care
while you're gone.
われわれは君の母親に過去最高のケアができるだろう。
And if l don't sign, what?
You going to erase my memory?
それで、もしサインしなかったら何？
記憶を消すのかい？
(CHUCKLES )
Something like that.
それもありえる。
Can l get some pants?
替えのパンツある？
HeIIo, I'm Dr: DanieI Jackson,
and behind me is a stargate:
やぁ、僕はダニエル・ジャクソン博士。
そして後ろにあるのがスターゲイトだ。
It was originaIIy buiIt miIIennia ago by
an aIien race who we caII the Ancients:
元は、エンシェントと呼ばれる1万年前の種族によって作られた。
Over the next few hours,
we'II be touching on some of the things:
ここ数時間、いろいろなものについて言及する。
There are 39 symboIs representing
star consteIIations as seen from Earth:
これらは地球から見える星座を表した39のシンボルだ。
When a connection is made
between two stargates,
スターゲイト間がつながったとき
an unstable energy vortex
emerges from the gate:::
不安定なエネルギーの渦がゲイトから出てくる。
Whoa !
わお。
:::and settles into the event horizon,
or ''puddle, ''as we Iike to call it:
そしてイベントホライズンに落ち着く。
Later, it was discovered
that using an eighth symboI
そして、数十万光年先の別の銀河にダイアルできる
wouId actually dial another galaxy
in hundreds of thousands of light years
8番目のシンボルを発見した。
via an interstellar wormhoIe:
銀河間のワームホールを等して
It is believed an unprecedented amount
of power is required
9番目のシンボルに到達するには前例にない
ほどのパワーが必要だと考えている
to reach the near-mythical ninth chevron:
The first six symboIs:::
最初の6つのシンボルだが、
Icarus Base was established
on a planet discovered two years ago
2年前に発見したイカルス基地では
to have a uniquely powerfuI core:
唯一の強力なコアがある。
The entire purpose of the project
is to hopefully one day
プロジェクトの目的は
diaI the nine chevron address
found in the Ancient database:
エンシェントのデータベースから見つかった
9つのアドレスをダイアルすることだ
Hi! I'm Dr: DanieI Jackson:
やぁ、僕はダニエル・ジャクソン博士。
Now, you've heard the term
''hyperspace'' for years:::
いま、君が聞いたハイパースペースとは
-Where are you?
-ELI:: It's top secret:
どこにいるの？
機密なんだ。
-Eli!
-l'm serious, Ma.
イーライ！
ほんとだよ、ママ。
l can't say anything more than that.
言えないんだ。
But l don't understand. Why could you not
at least tell me you were leaving?
けどわからないよ。どうして、何もいわずに
家をでたの？
l'm sorry, but did you get the letter from...
ごめんよ、けど、手紙が届いたろ…
Yeah, the Air Force: I got it:
あぁ、空軍からのね。
Are you in a plane now?
You sound like you're in an airplane.
飛行機に乗ってるの？
飛行機に乗ってるような音がするよ。
Uh, no. lt's nothing like that.
うん。いや、まぁそんなとこ。
l want you to know that
they're going to look after you.
後の面倒は彼らが見てくれるから。
Well, you didn't have to do this.
そぅ、わかった。
This is good.
よかった。
Really. lt's the kind of thing
l always dreamed of.
本当に、常に夢見てきたようなことなんだ。
-Hi.
-You mind?
やぁ。
ここいい？
-No, go ahead.
-Thank you.
えぇ、どうぞ。
サンキュー。
First time on a spaceship, too?
あなたも宇宙船は初めて？
Me? l've been on lots of various...
俺？
-Eli Wallace.
-l know.
イーライ・ウォレス。
知ってる。
-You've heard of me?
-l have.
Wow, that almost never happens.
And you are?
Chloe. l work for Alan Armstrong.
Senator of California?
Oh, yeah, yeah. l have heard of California.
(CHUCKLES )
My last job was in the burger and fries
field. How'd you line that up?
l was a political science major
at Harvard, so...
Mmm. l hear it's a good school.
For a while there l was at...
MlT. l know.
Really? What else have
they told you about me?
-What?
-l've seen this writing before.
-ln the game?
-Yeah.
(WHlRRlNG)
Sheesh. We're on a ship?
RUSH: The design is clearly Ancient,
in the truest sense of the word.
Launched hundreds of thousands
of years ago.
Dr. Rush?
Faster than light,
yet not through hyperspace.
-What are you doing?
-Who knows how far it's traveled.
Dr. Rush, l've got a lot of wounded.
We need to get home.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
(MECHANlCAL WHlRRlNG)
JOHANSEN ON RADIO::
Lieutenant Scott, come in:
Go ahead.
We've got a problem.
One of the air vents just shut down in here.
Copy that.
Yeah, the air's getting pretty thin
in here, too.
-What does that mean?
-That the life support system is failing.
And we should probably do
something about that.
EMlLY: Well, it's always just one more year.
lt's a command.
-Where?
-lt's a lot safer than other places l've been.
-You've put your time in, Everett.
-When this tour is over, l promise...
(ECHOlNG) You know what?
Never mind. Don't bother.
You always end up choosing
somewhere other than here.
(ECHOlNG) l am not choosing
my job over you.
How you can even say...
How you can even say that to me?
l love you, but l can't wait anymore.
l can't wait anymore.
Everett? Are you okay?
Sweetheart, baby, look at me.
(lNAUDlBLE)
Colonel? Colonel?
(GRUNTlNG)
Oh, my God.
Can't you do something?
He's having a seizure.
There's nothing l can do.
(BOTH MOANlNG)
ON RADIO:: Scott, this is CoIoneI Young:
Come in, pIease:
Our guests have arrived a few minutes
earIy, Lieutenant: What's your position?
Come on. Not yet. Not yet.
Lieutenant, drop whatever you're doing
and get your ass up here:
l'm on my way, sir.
Bye.
Holy...
Senator, it is my honor
to welcome you to lcarus Base.
Colonel. This is
my executive assistant, Chloe.
-lt's a pleasure to meet you, sir.
-The pleasure's mine.
She's also my daughter.
-You must be the...
-Contest winner, yeah. That is a big gun.
Rail gun. Five hundred rounds per minute.
This is Lieutenant Scott.
He's been assigned to you, Mr. Wallace.
Shall we go inside?
She's also my daughter.
-You must be the...
-Contest winner, yeah. That is a big gun.
Rail gun. 500 rounds per minute.
This is Lieutenant Scott.
He's been assigned to you, Mr. Wallace.
ARMSTRONG: You could probably
shave a few dollars off the budget
just by turning the heat down.
Actually, cooling the place
is what costs money, sir.
We're here because the core of the planet
generates so much power.
A lot of heat comes with that.
ELl: You ever get claustrophobic
down here?
SCOTT: Safer than the surface.
-Why?
-Dinosaurs, man.
Shall we go inside?
ELl: Unbelievable.
SCOTT: Yeah, it is.
lt's weird how fast you can start
to take something like this for granted.
-Really?
-No.
(ELl CHUCKLES )
ELl: Unbelievable.
SCOTT: Yeah, it is.
lt's weird how fast you can start
to take something like this for granted.
So, if a stargate can instantly
transport you to another planet,
why did we fly here on a spaceship?
Something to do with how this one's
tied into the planet for power.
why did we fly here on a spaceship?
Something to do with how this one's
tied into the planet for power.
Apparently, it's been modified
to only dial out
because incoming wormholes
are too dangerous.
You're the genius.
You can probably tell me better.
(LAUGHS ) All l did was solve a puzzle
in a video game.
Hey, you figured out something Dr. Rush
has been trying to figure out for months,
You're the genius.
You can probably tell me better.
(LAUGHS ) All l did was solve a puzzle
in a video game.
Hey, you figured out something Dr. Rush
has been trying to figure out for months,
which, by the way,
a lot of people were glad to see.
RUSH: And, of course,
you know Colonel Telford.
which, by the way,
a lot of people were glad to see.
RUSH: And, of course,
you know Colonel Telford.
-Ready for this, Colonel?
-You just give the word, sir.
Oh, l gave it quite a while ago, Colonel.
-Ready for this, Colonel?
-You just give the word, sir.
Oh, l gave it quite a while ago, Colonel.
l'm just here to see
how my $1 .6 billion is being spent.
(RUSH LAUGHS )
Very good. Thank you, everyone.
Dismissed.
l'm just here to see
how my $1 .6 billion is being spent.
(RUSH LAUGHS )
Very good. Thank you, everyone.
Dismissed.
As you know, up until now,
we have been unable to channel
the precise amount of power necessary
to unlock the stargate's
ninth and final chevron.
However, thanks to some ingenuity
from young Mr. Wallace here,
that problem has finally been solved.
YOUNG: We've heard that before.
This time we're sure.
That's what l figured out?
l embedded the mathematical problem
we had to solve into the game.
l then engineered your solution
into a practical, workable application.
-What say we get on with it?
-Absolutely. Sergeant Riley.
-RlLEY: Chevron one encoded.
-Sir.
(DlALlNG GATE)
We're dialing now?
-A test, to see if we can make a connection.
-RlLEY: Chevron one locked.
lf we do, we will send an automated
reconnaissance drone through.
We'll see what's on the other side.
RlLEY: Chevron two locked.
And then they'll go?
No, first, we close down again,
assess the data we receive,
-and then perhaps send the away team.
-lf it works.
RlLEY: Chevron four locked.
Until then,
they're just interested observers, like us.
RlLEY: Chevron five locked.
Chevron six encoded. Chevron six locked.
Chevron seven encoded.
Chevron seven locked.
Chevron eight encoded.
Chevron eight locked.
Chevron nine encoded.
-Whoa, what's going on?
-l don't know. We never got this far before.
Chevron nine... Chevron nine will not lock.
(COMPUTER BEEPlNG)
We matched the power requirements
down to the EMU. lt must work.
Power levels in the gate capacitors
are going into the red.
-Shut it down.
-No, wait, wait, wait.
RlLEY: We're reading fluctuations
in the output from the core...
Shut it down now.
(GATE POWERlNG DOWN)
(EXHALES )
-lt should have worked.
-Well, it didn't.
And drawing power
from the planet's core...
Dangerous? Yes. We're all aware of that...
Regardless of what's been spent
or what's at stake,
my first priority is to ensure
the safety of the people on this base.
Of course. Of course.
Eli, we'd best run through
your equations again.
lf you'll excuse me.
You are not seriously putting this on me!
Not my fault.
(PEOPLE CLAMORlNG)
SCOTT: People, you have to calm down.
Seriously, you have to calm down.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDlNG)
MAN: We got power!
WOMAN: Thank God!
Everybody's attention, please.
All right, please listen.
Hey, listen up!
(CHATTERlNG STOPS )
What is going on?
We are on an Ancient spaceship.
-MAN: What?
-That's all l've got.
Now, what that means is that...
That means you need to use the stargate
to get us all back home.
That is definitely
on the list of things to do, sir,
-but l think right now...
-You can consider that an order.
We are working on it, sir.
Now, l need to speak to the person
responsible for this. Where is Dr. Rush?
-Just shut up for a second, will you!
-How dare you talk to...
-Dad? Dad, please.
-WOMAN: Medic!
-Water? Water? Ouickly. Over here.
-Get...
CHLOE: Sit down.
ARMSTRONG: (GRUNTlNG) The pills.
(COUGHlNG)
Look, l'm sorry.
l'm just trying to explain the situation.
We are on a ship, but we have no idea
where we are in relation to Earth.
Now, with respect, sir,
the reason you might be having
a hard time breathing right now
is because the ship's life-support system
is not functioning properly.
Dr. Rush is working on that right now.
(ALL MURMURlNG)
Brody and Park?